Andreas Ziegler

Robotics & Computer Vision Researcher/Engineer

Zihlweg 22 8712 Stäfa Switzerland \Box +41 (0)79 581 46 90 **☑** 062.127@gmail.com 3 andreasaziegler.github.io in andreas-ziegler



Summary

I am passioned about a mix of robotics and computer vision research and industrial/commercial applications. My vision is to develop novel algorithms and make them work on real robots. I enjoy working independently on researcher and engineer projects, but I appreciate the opportunity to exchange ideas with a variety of individuals from various backgrounds.

Personal details

Date of birth 25.03.1988

Nationality Swiss

Education

05.2021- PhD Candidate, University of Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany

Thesis: Event-based vision for fast robot control

- In collaboration with Sony AI Zürich
- O Thesis supervisors: Prof. Dr. Andreas Zell and Prof. Dr. Andreas Geiger

09.2014–04.2018 MSc ETH in EEIT, ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland

Specialized in: Robotics, Computer Vision and Machine Learning

Master Thesis: A Representation for Exploration that is Robustto State Estimate Drift

- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Roland Siegwart and Prof. Dr. Davide Scaramuzza
- Resulted in [4]

Semester Project 2: Map Fusion for Collaborative UAV SLAM

- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Roland Siegwart and Prof. Dr. Margarita Chli
- Semester Project 1: Robust object tracking in 3D by fusing ultra-wideband and vision
- O Examiner: Prof. Dr. Luc Van Gool and Prof. Dr. Otmar Hilliges

09.2009–09.2013 BSc FHO in Electrical Engineering, University of Applied Science Eastern Switzerland (HSR), Rapperswil, Switzerland

> Specialized in: Digital Signal and Image Processing, Embedded Systems and Software Engineering and Mobile Communication

09.2011-08.2012 Exchange year, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China

Courses taken: Chinese language, Electrical engineering and Computer Science

Independent Coursework

edX DT-01x: Self-Driving Cars with Duckietown by ETHx on edX. Specialization Certificate earned on August 15, 2021

Coursera Deep Learning, a 5-course specialization by deeplearning ai on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on March 16, 2018

Autonomous Mobile Robots by ETHx on edX. Certificate earned on April 17, 2014

Work experience

08.2022–10.2022 Computer Vision & ML Research Intern, Prophesee, Paris, France, 100%

Worked on slow motion from frame and event data under the supervison of Dr. Amos Sironi

Technologies used: Python, PyTorch, OpenCV, numpy, git, Atlassian tools

06.2021-present PhD Candidate, University of Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany, 100%

- Working on Event-based computer vision for fast robot control in collaboration with Sony AI Zürich
- Supervision of MSc and BSc students
- Teaching Assistant

Technologies used: C++, Python, Julia, PyTorch, OpenCV, numpy, Eigen, ROS1/2, git,

09.2018–05.2021 Robotics Engineer, MT Robot AG, Zwingen, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- Development of a computer vision based safety field intrusion detection system
- Improvement of a multi robot collision avoidance system
- Development and maintenance of software for automated guided vehicle (AGVs), including topics such as multi sensor fusion, mapping, path planning, (multi robot) obstacle avoidance, etc.
- O Deputy Scrum Master

Technologies used: C++, Python, ROS1/2, DDS, OpenCV, CMake, git, Atlassian tools

06.2018-09.2018 Research Assistant, University of Zürich, Robotics and Perception Group, Zurich, Switzerland, 100%

Continued working on my master thesis project which lead to [4]

04.2018–06.2018 Research Associate Intern, Disney Research Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland, 100% Integrated a Leica total station in an existing ROS setup within the PaintCopter project.

Technologies used: C++, Python, ROS, Ceres, CMake, git

02.2018–03.2018 Research Assistant, Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zurich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%

> Developed an LED light controller for a microscope setup which contributed to [3]. Technologies used: C++, Qt, wxWidgets, CMake, git

03.2017-08.2017 Computer Vision & Robotics Research Intern, Pix4D SA, Lausanne, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- Worked on indoor navigation for UAVs
- Implementation of a filtering method for a robust target detection
- Participation on an indoor mapping project with an industrial partner
- Investigation of barcode localization and detection algorithms for automatic inventory
- Participation on a development of a target detection library for radiometric corrections
- Worked on various computer vision applications (Barcode localization/detection, 3D reconstruction, Camera calibration)

Technologies used: C++, ROS, OpenCV, Eigen, Conan, CMake, Jenkins, git

08.2015–06.2018 Software Engineer & System Administrator, Accelerom AG, Zürich, Switzerland, 20%-30%

> Technologies used: Java, Groovy, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, Grails, Hibernate, MySQL, git, Redmine, Tomcat, Apache, SAMBA

02.2014–08.2015 Research Assistant, Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zurich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%/20%

Continued my work, provided further consulting and maintenance.

11.2013–02.2014 Research Assistant (Civil service), Computer Assisted Research and Development, University Hospital Balgrist, Zürich, Switzerland, 100% Worked on segmentation algorithms for computer-assisted surgical planning

Technologies used: Matlab, C#, VTK, CVS

08.2013–11.2013 Research Assistant (Civil service), Laboratory for Orthopaedic Biomechanics at the University and ETH Zurich, Zürich, Switzerland, 100%

Accomplished tasks:

- O Extended and adapted a microscope control software which contributed to [2]
- O Developed and implemented a stretcher control software

Technologies used: C++, Qt, wxWidgets, CMake, git

08.2008–03.2009 Computer Science Intern, ERPsourcing AG, Wallisellen, Switzerland, 100%

08.2004–08.2008 Electronics Engineer Apprentice, Hch. Kündig & Cie. AG, Rüti ZH, Switzerland, 100%

Publications

- [1] A. Ziegler, D. Teigland, J. Tebbe, T. Gossard, and A. Zell, *Real-time event simulation with frame-based cameras*, 2022. DOI: 10.48550/ARXIV.2209.04634. [Online]. Available: https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.04634.
- [2] A. Horvath, A. Ziegler, S. Gerhard, et al., "Focus on time: Dynamic imaging reveals stretch-dependent cell relaxation and nuclear deformation," Biophysical Journal, Jan. 2021. DOI: 10.1016/j.bpj.2021.01.020.
- [3] A. N. Horvath, A. A. Ziegler, S. Gerhard, et al., "Time-controlled multichannel dynamic traction imaging of biaxially stretched adherent cells," Mar. 2020. DOI: 10.1101/2020.03.02.972919. [Online]. Available: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.03.02.972919.
- [4] T. Cieslewski, A. Ziegler, and D. Scaramuzza, "Exploration without global consistency using local volume consolidation," in *IFRR International Symposium on Robotics Research (ISRR)*, Hanoi, 2019, IFRR: IEEE, Oct. 2019. [Online]. Available: https://doi.org/10.5167/uzh-197724.

Languages

German Mother tongue

English Excellent, Level C1

French Good, Level B1,

Chinese Basics, Level A1

Korean Basics, Level A2

Technical skills

Languages C++, Python, Julia, C, Java

Software packages OpenCV, ROS1/2, PyTorch, Eigen, boost, DDS, pcl, scikit-learn, wxWidgets, Qt, MATLAB

Hobbies

Sports Wing Chun Kung Fu, Yoga, Jogging, Mountaineering

Music Drums, Piano, Vocals

Extra-Curricular activities

Board member *jevp (Junge Evangelische Volkspartei Schweiz)

- Foodsaver at Foodsharing
- o Managing a Labdoo hub